It's been too long, dahlings.
Incredibles 2 is a action, adventure, animation film directed by Brad Bird.
Elastigirl springs into action to save the day, while Mr.
Incredible faces his greatest challenge yet – taking care
of the problems of his three children.
Bob Parr / Mr. Incredible (voice), played by Craig T. Nelson.
Helen Parr / Elastigirl (voice), played by Holly Hunter.
Violet Parr (voice), played by Sarah Vowell.
Dashiell 'Dash' Parr (voice), played by Huck Milner.
Evelyn Deavor (voice), played by Catherine Keener.
Jack-Jack Parr (voice), played by Eli Fucile.
Incredibles 2 is a 2018 American animated superhero film produced by
Pixar Animation Studios for Walt Disney Pictures.
The sequel to The Incredibles (2004), it was written and directed by Brad Bird.
Holly Hunter, Craig T.
Nelson, Sarah Vowell, and Samuel L.
Jackson reprise their roles from the first film, with Huck Milner, Bob
Odenkirk, Catherine Keener, and Jonathan Banks joining the cast.
The film follows the Incredibles as they try to restore the public's
trust in superheroes while balancing family life.
Following the success of The Incredibles, Bird postponed
development on a sequel to work on other films.
He attempted to distinguish the script from superhero films and superhero television series released
since the first film, focusing on the family dynamic rather than the superhero genre.
Incredibles 2 premiered in Los Angeles on June 5, 2018, and was
theatrically released in the United States on June 15, 2018.
The film received positive reviews from critics, with praise for its animation,
humor, voice acting, action sequences, writing, and musical score.
The film made $182.7 million in its opening weekend, setting the record for best debut for an animated film, and grossed over $1.2 billion worldwide, making it the fourth-highest-grossing film of 2018, the
second-highest-grossing animated film, and the 15th-highest-grossing film of all time during its theatrical run, along with being Pixar's third film to gross $1 billion after Finding Dory and Toy Story 3.
It also became the highest-grossing animated film in the United States and Canada as well as
the highest-grossing Pixar film until the release of Inside Out 2 in 2024.
Incredibles 2 was named by the National Board of
Review as the Best Animated Film of 2018.
The film was nominated for Best Animated Feature Film at the 76th Golden Globe Awards and
91st Academy Awards, but lost both awards to Spider-Man: Into the Spider-Verse.
The film was also the winner of the 2019 Kids' Choice
Award for Favorite Animated Movie.
A sequel, titled Incredibles 3, is in development
and is slated for a 2028 release.
The film explores themes of married couple, superhero, cartoon, villain, sequel.